Ralph Whitbeck

Developer Evangelist at Atlassian

Summary

A driven and experienced speaker, writer, trainer, and developer based in Rochester, NY. He's been in the web development industry since 1997 and in the open source community since 2009. Currently he is leading the training department at appendTo, a board member for the jQuery Foundation and is the Developer Relations lead for the jQuery Project.

Coordinated with conference coordinators to include pre-conference training sessions resulting in hundreds of attendees over 3 different conferences with a combined total of \$65K in revenue both within the US and abroad.

Created our companies first online community conference 'Modern Web Conference' within a short timeframe of 3 months resulting in hundreds of global attendees through speaker selection/recruitment, marketing execution, partnerships/sponsors and event coordination.

Engaged in regular technical and business interactions with all levels of the enterprise at community events and conferences leading to training department revenue that was net positive for both public and private training opportunities in the first year.

Experience

Developer Evangelist at Atlassian

December 2014 - Present

Vice President of Training at appendTo

October 2013 - October 2014 (1 year)

As the Vice President of Training it was my responsibility to lead the training department in its strategic direction. Additionally, I was responsible for budget, sales, partnerships as well as curating and delivering content for the program. appendTo Training specialized in training for front-end technologies like jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and Responsive Web Design to name a few.

Modern Web Advocate for appendTo's Tools and Services at appendTo, LLC

December 2012 - October 2013 (10 months)

For a number of months in 2012 I was asked to help with evangelizing and marketing the appendTo message. I was responsible for the blog, social, conference talks that related back to appendTo and higher level strategic marketing. Additionally, I was responsible for creating and running sponsorship booths at various conferences.

Director of Professional Services at appendTo, LLC

July 2012 - December 2012 (5 months)

Responsible for operational fulfillment of the Professional Services Business Unit.

Senior Developer at appendTo, LLC

October 2011 - July 2012 (9 months)

Front-end developer with experience with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript (jQuery). Project management of projects.

Senior Web Application Engineer at BrandLogic

May 1999 - October 2011 (12 years 5 months)

- * Lead Developer Provide leadership for development amongst many team members for a given project. Responsible for making sure the account managers have the proper knowledge to be able to relay development project status to clients. Work with other strategists to analyze and develop sound web strategies for client sites. Work with designers to help them understand the functionality that will be implemented from their designs. Work with developers to ensure that we are all working together and are focused on delivering quality code that is on time and on budget.
- * Web application developer Ability to program complex web application systems in ASP.NET, C# and SQL Server to meet client requirements. Ability to use client side technologies like XHTML, CSS and JavaScript to be able to implement the client approved designs from the designers.
- * Internship manager and recruiter Manage and oversee the development of our internship program. I interview and hire up to two interns every three to six months that are sound technically and professionally. Their internship teaches them to be professional programmers that allow them to work under my direct supervision on high profile client sites that give them valuable real-world experience. Some have stayed on and became our core developers at BrandLogic, others have used this experience to be successful at companies like: IBM, Mozilla, Google, Apple, VMWare, CurrentTV, Tapulous and Yahoo.

Web Developer

December 2002 - August 2007 (4 years 8 months)

Worked with a company to maintain and develop a custom Content Management System.

Web Developer at Rochester Institute of Technology

December 1997 - May 1999 (1 year 5 months)

Was in charge of programming the main RIT site as well many department subsites around campus. I ensured all the departments stayed on Brand with the main school site.

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

BS, Information Technology, 1996 - 1999

Niagara County Community College

AS, Computer Science, 1994 - 1996

Activities and Societies: Computer Club (President)

Ralph Whitbeck

Developer Evangelist at Atlassian



Contact Ralph on LinkedIn